<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Redeeming Communities</title>
    <link>https://redeemingcommunities.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Redeeming Communities</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Redeeming Communities</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://redeemingcommunities.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>https://redeemingcommunities.com/talk/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redeemingcommunities.com/talk/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Academic&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further talk details can easily be added to this page using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are We Fully Partaking</title>
      <link>https://redeemingcommunities.com/post/are-we-fully-partaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 11:15:49 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redeemingcommunities.com/post/are-we-fully-partaking/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-should-we-partake-in-redeeming-society&#34;&gt;Why Should We Partake In Redeeming Society?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we want to see change in our God given communities and society, we need to go beyond holding onto the gospel as our own personal plan of salvation. By remaining passive in our salvation, we minimise God’s ongoing relationship towards creation, and his concern with mankind. We are all called to participate in his mission which is centred on redemption towards those who are lost, oppressed and suffering injustice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to think upon the &amp;lsquo;good works&amp;rsquo; that have been prepared for us in advance before creation (Ephesians 2:10). These good works should be an outworking of our faith, and an extension of the grace and mercy given to us. These include acts of mercy, charity, and service, which are given as service to those individuals, and communities affected by acts of injustice and oppression from the effects of the fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our gifts and talents are to be used to help to bring relief to the social ills that surround us. To help in the redeeming of society, we approach issues using kingdom principles, expressing the love of God, giving people a foretaste of God’s kingdom here on earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to share the full gospel of the kingdom - which includes being saved by grace – if not, we are only telling half the story and using it to gain entry to heaven.  Let us abandon our individualised Christianity and not be like our western individualistic culture and instead show the world that God does care deeply about what is happening in the world and the individual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like what Dick Staub writes in his book &lt;em&gt;The Culturally Savvy Christian&lt;/em&gt;, he shows how popular media has diverted our attention from issues that matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Humans sit in front of television sets, passively watching human misery unfold, while just outside their door, down the street, or in an apartment next door, a real person faces the same problem and there is no one to help them because we’re all preoccupied with our favourite characters on reality TV”&lt;/em&gt; (p.7).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like this quote as an example of how one medium can have a huge influence in making society passive towards the real world, and numbing our reality. Just imagine how living fully engage in our purpose would reverse the effect we would have our everyday lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we live the gospel message fully, we become more motivated by the love of Christ, then we can engage fully. Until we engage as a redemptive community of believers we won&amp;rsquo;t be able to provide solutions for society that only the ‘&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=1+Corinthians+15&amp;amp;version=ESV&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;good news&lt;/a&gt;’ can provide. However, taking on a redemptive approach is a willingness to take on real world problems, seeking remedies for social and individual problems using a biblical world-view to find truth to solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no relief for anyone if we just watch the world go by, when we have the answers for a world that weeps and groans for redemption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redemptive Imagination</title>
      <link>https://redeemingcommunities.com/post/redemptive-imagination/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 21:45:49 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redeemingcommunities.com/post/redemptive-imagination/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cultivating-a-redemptive-imagination&#34;&gt;Cultivating a Redemptive Imagination&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of the redemptive imagination is to look at the broken fabric of lives and society around us and to see something else. Re-imagining what it would look like if the Kingdom of God broke into our possibility. To build our own redemptive imagination, we have to imagine what possibility does God has for us in our everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Redemptive work is so important for us as Christians right now in the environments that we spend more time in than anywhere else. This could be in the workplace, our vocations, place of study, or in the home. These are the places that we get to create the world in which we inhabit, and where we get to interact with the values, world views and perspectives of others. It is in some of these places that we spend most of our time and learn, and experience life – the good and the bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in an ever evolving society of radical change, a lot of societal progress is actually being defined without the gospel in mind. Together, if we can cultivate a redemptive imagination with the gospel and bring this mindset into a lot of the settings we are already in or leading, then we get the privilege of leading what’s not good, into something that is good, with the “good news”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first, I think that we need to reintroduce the ideas and principles of the Kingdom of God, as I think we are missing the power behind the knowledge of it – so when we pray “your kingdom come, your will be done on earth as it is in heaven” we know that we are operating in the power of it, through Jesus Christ. Then we can take flight in the promises and purposes of God’s Kingdom and influence change around us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We live in a world that is really crying out for change, although most people are less interested in hearing the gospel, and are more interested in seeing it lived out and how it is embodied in our communities and daily life. It is Gods desire to manifest his wisdom and nature on the earth, through us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is vital for us to understand our place in God’s kingdom, which gives us understanding in our vocations (work), the place where God has put us. I also believe that we need to change our mindset and see how we are a “gift” from God to those around us, especially in our workplaces. This can feel so counter-intuitive to us in our environments, but we have all been given the tools, talents and mandate to bestow on the world, God&amp;rsquo;s richness of character and grace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just imagine what possibilities you could create for someone, or the change and impact you could make when you try something a little different using your redemptive imagination and God breaks in. There will be sacrifices, just like how Jesus laid down his life to restore mankind to God. This is how we partake in redemptive work, as the hands and feet of Jesus, with commitment to break out a new possibility for the kingdom here on earth as it is in heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
