<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Redeeming Communities</title>
    <link>https://redeemingcommunities.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Redeeming Communities</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Redeeming Communities</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://redeemingcommunities.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>https://redeemingcommunities.com/talk/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redeemingcommunities.com/talk/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Academic&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further talk details can easily be added to this page using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living Without Purpose</title>
      <link>https://redeemingcommunities.com/post/living-without-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 16:45:49 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redeemingcommunities.com/post/living-without-purpose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where there is no revelation [vision], the people cast off restraint&amp;hellip;” Proverbs 29:18&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where there is a lack of purpose and vision, impending tragedy follows. The absence of purpose and the lost of significance, impacts individuals, families, communities and society. It can affect the levels of trust which can make the difference between life and death to an individual or to community. It breeds a lack of confidence, discouragement, frustration, lack of creativity and disillusionment in these places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Purpose is the motivator, it draws out confidence, untapped creativity, gives people the courage to bring change, not only in their own lives, but those around them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When God created mankind, each person was designed with a purpose, its God given, it makes us unique. Purpose gives us hope and makes us feel that our life counts for something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without purpose we only exist, we have no passion for living, or have a reason to wake up in the morning. This is the story of many people today. There are those seem to live successful lives, yet inside feel a void. A high percentage of people need to know that their life matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We live in a world that breeds fear, stress, depression and hopelessness, and with each generation that is coming through, their sense of purpose is losing its value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The influence of the mediated culture has normalised wrong values and morals and built an unachievable identity of acceptance. It has directed the family and social norms, and what makes a healthy society. The moral fabric of society is being so stretched and bent out of shape, that it challenges God’s original design and purpose for humankind and creation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Solomon reveals, where there is no purpose [vision], this has a negative impact on society, both at a personal (micro) level and corporate (macro) level. My belief is, when a person finds their purpose at a personal level, positive change happens at the macro level, if not the negative impact increases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our communities become unfriendly and social problems breed, with the lack of purpose. People see no reason for living, they have no discipline in maintaining a moral compass, no commitment to each other, have no respect for each other. Living and moving amongst people who lack their sense of significance, creates an atmosphere of deep emptiness and failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we want to bring positive change in our communities, we can help people to discover their purpose in life, and their reason for being born. There are many people who have undiscovered gifts and talents, suffering wasted lives heading towards lives of crime, drugs, poverty and many other social problems.
Many of these people have gold in their lives, and have answers to problems that need to be solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone has a right for hope in this life, and know that their life counts for something, otherwise God wouldn&amp;rsquo;t of designed us for a purpose. So many people are reaching for something, (or trying) though ultimately they need Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is, we ourselves can find our life purpose and God given call, and start living our God given purpose and do what we have been put on this earth to do. Even better, we can help others around us to find purpose and find a life worth living.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panning For Gold</title>
      <link>https://redeemingcommunities.com/publication/panning-for-gold/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 16:45:49 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redeemingcommunities.com/publication/panning-for-gold/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A frustrated young man went to see the wise man in his village. “I don’t know what to do with my life. How do I find my purpose?” the young man asked. “Follow me,” said the old man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Silently, they trudged together to a far away river where they found dozens of prospectors panning for gold. “There are three types of prospectors here,” the sage said. “What do you mean?” the young man inquired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There are those who strike gold straight away. Excited, they take their plunder, cash it in and live comfortably for the rest of their lives. Then there are those who pan for years. They know that there is gold here and they have seen others strike it rich, so they persist until they too find the gold that they’ve been searching for.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What about the third type?” asked the young man. “They are the individuals who get frustrated that they haven’t found what they are looking for, so after a day, a week or a year or more, they give up, walk away and never find gold.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slightly confused, the young man asked, “What has this got to do with finding my purpose?” “Ah yes, the age-old question.” the old man smiled and looked his companion in the eye. “There are those in life who look for their purpose and seem to find it almost immediately. From a young age they have a clear sense of purpose and pursue their dreams with energy and enthusiasm. Some others have to look a bit harder, perhaps for many years, but if they persist and keep looking, they will find something to live for.  Finally, there are those who want to know their purpose, but they become frustrated with the search and give up too soon, returning to a life of meaningless wandering.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Can everyone find their purpose?”&lt;br /&gt;
“Is there gold in the river?”  the wise man responded.&lt;br /&gt;
“So, how do I find my own purpose?”&lt;br /&gt;
“Keep looking.”&lt;br /&gt;
“But what if I want to find it quicker?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Son, there are no guarantees that you will be able to find it quickly, the only guarantee is that if you give up and stop looking for it, you’ll never find it.” The young man looked despondent, feeling that he had wasted his time with the old man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He felt a reassuring hand on his shoulder, “I can sense your frustration, but let me assure you, if you can find your true calling in life, you will live with passion, make the world a better place, be richer than you could imagine and feel as though the very face of God Himself is smiling upon you.  That may happen next week, next year or in the years ahead, but the search will be worth it and your life will never be the same again. So for now, your purpose is to find your purpose.”&lt;br /&gt;
“Thanks.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, and there’s one other thing that I forgot to mention.”&lt;br /&gt;
“What’s that?”&lt;br /&gt;
“Just as those men and women need to get down to the river with a pan to find their gold, so we need to remain active to find our purposes, we don’t find it sitting around at home doing nothing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was getting late, so the two men turned for home and began their long walk back to the village. As they walked, the young man was deep in thought about what he had just learned, and the wise man smiled to himself, knowing that conversations like this were an important part of living his own purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, over to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know your purpose for life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you still looking?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or have you given up?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darren Poke – Better Life Coaching&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Coaching Resources</title>
      <link>https://redeemingcommunities.com/publication/the-coaching-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 02:45:49 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redeemingcommunities.com/publication/the-coaching-room/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;isotope projects-container&#34;&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;project-card project-item isotope-item&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;card&#34;&gt; 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://redeemingcommunities.com/publication/panning-for-gold/&#34; title=&#34;Panning For Gold&#34; class=&#34;card-image hover-overlay&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;../panning-for-gold/featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;Panning For Gold&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive kims-selected-publications&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;div class=&#34;card-text&#34;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../panning-for-gold/&#34; &gt;Panning For Gold&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;card-desription&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;A Story About Finding Your Purpose in Life.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!--
&lt;div class=&#34;project-card project-item isotope-item&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;card&#34;&gt; 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://redeemingcommunities.com/publication/docker-security/&#34; title=&#34;Docker Security - Quick Reference&#34; class=&#34;card-image hover-overlay&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://redeemingcommunities.com/img/publication/title_page_docker-security_720.png&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Security - Quick Reference&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive kims-selected-publications&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;div class=&#34;card-text&#34;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://redeemingcommunities.com/publication/docker-security/&#34; &gt;Docker Security &amp;nbsp; - &amp;nbsp; Quick Reference &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;card-desription&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The security defaults of Docker are established to get you up and running (“just work”) quickly, rather than being the most secure. In this book we improve upon many default configurations. Including knowledge gleaned from the Docker Security Team Lead. &lt;b&gt;This entire content is included in The VPS chapter of Holistic InfoSec for Web Developers F1.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;project-card project-item isotope-item&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;card&#34;&gt; 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://f0.holisticinfosecforwebdevelopers.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Holistic Info-Sec for Web Developers Fascicle 0&#34; class=&#34;card-image hover-overlay&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://redeemingcommunities.com/img/publication/title_page_f0_720.png&#34; alt=&#34;Holistic Info-Sec for Web Developers Fascicle 0&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive kims-selected-publications&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;div class=&#34;card-text&#34;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f0.holisticinfosecforwebdevelopers.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Holistic Info-Sec for Web Developers Fascicle 0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;card-desription&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The first part of a three part book series providing broad and in-depth coverage on what Software Developers/Engineers, DevOps Engineers and architects need to know in order to create robust, reliable, maintainable and secure software, networks and other, that are delivered continuously, on time, with no nasty surprises.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
      
&lt;div class=&#34;project-card project-item isotope-item&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;card&#34;&gt; 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://f1.holisticinfosecforwebdevelopers.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Holistic Info-Sec for Web Developers Fascicle 1&#34; class=&#34;card-image hover-overlay&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://redeemingcommunities.com/img/publication/title_page_f1_720.png&#34; alt=&#34;Holistic Info-Sec for Web Developers Fascicle 1&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive kims-selected-publications&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;div class=&#34;card-text&#34;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f1.holisticinfosecforwebdevelopers.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Holistic Info-Sec for Web Developers Fascicle 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;card-desription&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The second part of a three part book series providing broad and in-depth coverage on what Software Developers/Engineers, DevOps Engineers and architects need to know in order to create robust, reliable, maintainable and secure software, networks and other, that are delivered continuously, on time, with no nasty surprises.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 

&lt;div class=&#34;project-card project-item isotope-item&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 20px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;card&#34;&gt; 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://f2.holisticinfosecforwebdevelopers.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Holistic Info-Sec for Web Developers Fascicle 2&#34; class=&#34;card-image hover-overlay&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://redeemingcommunities.com/img/publication/title_page_f2_720.png&#34; alt=&#34;Holistic Info-Sec for Web Developers Fascicle 2&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive kims-selected-publications&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt; 
    &lt;div class=&#34;card-text&#34;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f2.holisticinfosecforwebdevelopers.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Holistic Info-Sec for Web Developers Fascicle 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;card-desription&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The third part of a three part book series providing broad and in-depth coverage on what Software Developers/Engineers, DevOps Engineers and architects need to know in order to create robust, reliable, maintainable and secure software, networks and other, that are delivered continuously, on time, with no nasty surprises.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are We Fully Partaking</title>
      <link>https://redeemingcommunities.com/post/are-we-fully-partaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 11:15:49 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redeemingcommunities.com/post/are-we-fully-partaking/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-should-we-partake-in-redeeming-society&#34;&gt;Why Should We Partake In Redeeming Society?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we want to see change in our God given communities and society, we need to go beyond holding onto the gospel as our own personal plan of salvation. By remaining passive in our salvation, we minimise God’s ongoing relationship towards creation, and his concern with mankind. We are all called to participate in his mission which is centred on redemption towards those who are lost, oppressed and suffering injustice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to think upon the &amp;lsquo;good works&amp;rsquo; that have been prepared for us in advance before creation (Ephesians 2:10). These good works should be an outworking of our faith, and an extension of the grace and mercy given to us. These include acts of mercy, charity, and service, which are given as service to those individuals, and communities affected by acts of injustice and oppression from the effects of the fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our gifts and talents are to be used to help to bring relief to the social ills that surround us. To help in the redeeming of society, we approach issues using kingdom principles, expressing the love of God, giving people a foretaste of God’s kingdom here on earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to share the full gospel of the kingdom - which includes being saved by grace – if not, we are only telling half the story and using it to gain entry to heaven.  Let us abandon our individualised Christianity and not be like our western individualistic culture and instead show the world that God does care deeply about what is happening in the world and the individual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like what Dick Staub writes in his book &lt;em&gt;The Culturally Savvy Christian&lt;/em&gt;, he shows how popular media has diverted our attention from issues that matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Humans sit in front of television sets, passively watching human misery unfold, while just outside their door, down the street, or in an apartment next door, a real person faces the same problem and there is no one to help them because we’re all preoccupied with our favourite characters on reality TV”&lt;/em&gt; (p.7).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like this quote as an example of how one medium can have a huge influence in making society passive towards the real world, and numbing our reality. Just imagine how living fully engage in our purpose would reverse the effect we would have our everyday lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we live the gospel message fully, we become more motivated by the love of Christ, then we can engage fully. Until we engage as a redemptive community of believers we won&amp;rsquo;t be able to provide solutions for society that only the ‘&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=1+Corinthians+15&amp;amp;version=ESV&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;good news&lt;/a&gt;’ can provide. However, taking on a redemptive approach is a willingness to take on real world problems, seeking remedies for social and individual problems using a biblical world-view to find truth to solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no relief for anyone if we just watch the world go by, when we have the answers for a world that weeps and groans for redemption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redemptive Imagination</title>
      <link>https://redeemingcommunities.com/post/redemptive-imagination/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 21:45:49 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://redeemingcommunities.com/post/redemptive-imagination/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cultivating-a-redemptive-imagination&#34;&gt;Cultivating a Redemptive Imagination&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of the redemptive imagination is to look at the broken fabric of lives and society around us and to see something else. Re-imagining what it would look like if the Kingdom of God broke into our possibility. To build our own redemptive imagination, we have to imagine what possibility does God has for us in our everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Redemptive work is so important for us as Christians right now in the environments that we spend more time in than anywhere else. This could be in the workplace, our vocations, place of study, or in the home. These are the places that we get to create the world in which we inhabit, and where we get to interact with the values, world views and perspectives of others. It is in some of these places that we spend most of our time and learn, and experience life – the good and the bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in an ever evolving society of radical change, a lot of societal progress is actually being defined without the gospel in mind. Together, if we can cultivate a redemptive imagination with the gospel and bring this mindset into a lot of the settings we are already in or leading, then we get the privilege of leading what’s not good, into something that is good, with the “good news”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first, I think that we need to reintroduce the ideas and principles of the Kingdom of God, as I think we are missing the power behind the knowledge of it – so when we pray “your kingdom come, your will be done on earth as it is in heaven” we know that we are operating in the power of it, through Jesus Christ. Then we can take flight in the promises and purposes of God’s Kingdom and influence change around us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We live in a world that is really crying out for change, although most people are less interested in hearing the gospel, and are more interested in seeing it lived out and how it is embodied in our communities and daily life. It is Gods desire to manifest his wisdom and nature on the earth, through us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is vital for us to understand our place in God’s kingdom, which gives us understanding in our vocations (work), the place where God has put us. I also believe that we need to change our mindset and see how we are a “gift” from God to those around us, especially in our workplaces. This can feel so counter-intuitive to us in our environments, but we have all been given the tools, talents and mandate to bestow on the world, God&amp;rsquo;s richness of character and grace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just imagine what possibilities you could create for someone, or the change and impact you could make when you try something a little different using your redemptive imagination and God breaks in. There will be sacrifices, just like how Jesus laid down his life to restore mankind to God. This is how we partake in redemptive work, as the hands and feet of Jesus, with commitment to break out a new possibility for the kingdom here on earth as it is in heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
